github.com/maryfarner18 medium.com/@maryfarner maryfarner.me

Full stack software engineer experienced in web development, with background in CS and experience in finance and fitness. Possess strong people and project management skills to help small teams drive growth and success.

EDUCATION

Yale University, New Haven, CT

2012 - 2016

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science & Mathematics - GPA: 3.54/4.00

Women's Varsity Crew, walk-on, 2015 & 2016 Ivy League Champion, 7th Place NCAA Championship 2016

Flatiron School, New York, NY

2019 - 2020

Web Development Immersive Course

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Developer: Milo Pets, New York, NY

2020 - Present

- Contributes to development of the Ruby / React web application, including development of new features, support of legacy code, dev-ops management, and technical support including triaging bugs in real-time.
- Collaborates with the product team as well as end-users to develop new features and requirements and manages the product development and engineering implementation of primary third party integrations.

Project Manager + Regional Director: Chelsea Piers, New York, NY

2018 - 2019

- Managed enterprise-wide technology turnaround including assessment of the user experience and web presence, financial reporting and back office software tools, and business operational software.
- Managed 80+ instructors and three full-time employees with oversight of hiring and payroll processes.

FX Forwards Trader, Analyst: Bank of America Merrill Lynch, New York, NY

2017 - 2018

- Funded daily FX positions and supported senior traders in market-making, pricing, reporting, and risk management.
- Passed all requisite FINRA Licensing Exams (Series 7 and Series 63).

Computer Scientist; Top Secret Security Clearance: USAF Research Lab, Rome, NY 2014, 2015, 2016 – 2017

• Processed and analyzed data to provide for informed decision-making and increased security in AF-wide operations.

HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS

Diagnostics and Imaging API Integrations [Milo]:

- Built out full interfaces for three separate APIs from veterinary lab companies, utilizing both HTTP JSON and XML Soap protocols.
- Implemented full stack solution for placing, tracking, and reviewing diagnostics and radiology in the app, removing the need for users to interact with external applications.

Automated Messaging Platform [Milo]:

• Created time and event based automated text messaging processes for system reminders, follow ups, and notifications, easing the burden of manual communications on users.

Maintenance and Growth of Third-Party Integrations [Milo]:

Maintained and built upon interfaces with third party APIs including Stripe, Twilio, Shippo, Printnode, Delighted.

SKILLS AND INTERESTS

Technical Skills

Ruby, Rails, Typescript, GraphQL, JavaScript, React, NodeJS, Java, Python, C, C++, SQLite, PostgreSQL, Linux, SQL, HTML, CSS, PHP, Slim, AWS

Fitness

2nd place woman: 2016 Brooklyn Marathon; 2021 TCS NYC Marathon finisher [3:03]; 2018 Boston Marathon finisher; 2nd in age group: IRONMAN 70.3 Lake Placid 2018. IRONMAN 140.6 Tulsa, May 2022.